迭戈·蒙罗伊，我们在这里欢迎您来到体育中心的独家首映式。
Diego Monroy, we here welcome you to this exclusive premiere of Sport Center.
Diego Monroy, nosotros acá les damos la bienvenida a ustedes a este estreno exclusivo de Sport Center.
Fideo 和 María 在我们的频道上携手并进。
with Fideo and María hand in hand on our channel.
con Fideo y María mano a mano en nuestro canal.
在这里你有它。
Here you have it.
Acá lo tenés.
好吧，安吉尔，让我们稍微了解一下天气，你觉得呢？
Well Ángel, let's get into the weather a little, do you think?
Bueno Ángel, vamos a meternos un poco en clima ¿Te parece?
嗯，让我们分享一下
Well, let's share
Bueno, a compartir
困难的同义词是什么？
Difficult is synonymous with what?
¿Difícil es sinónimo de qué?
不用买靴子...
Not having to buy boots...
No tener para comprar botines...
我没有人一起训练，我有机会脱颖而出，从下面走出来，我非常感谢每一个人。
I had no one to train with, I had the opportunity to emerge, to come out from below and I am very grateful to everyone.
No tenía con quien entrenar, tuve la posibilidad de surgir, de salir desde abajo y estoy muy agradecido a todos.
能够继续这样下去，并有机会继续向国家成年队展示。
to be able to continue this way and have the opportunity to continue demonstrating to the Senior National Team.
para poder seguir esta manera y tener la oportunidad de seguir demostrando a la Selección Mayor.
我骑着来了，一直骑着，不断地把头撞到墙上，不断地撞，直到今天它摔坏了。
I came riding and kept riding, kept hitting my head against the wall, kept hitting it, until today it broke.
Me llegué montando y seguí montando, seguí dando la cabeza contra la pared, la seguí dando, hasta que hoy se rompió.
作为世界冠军，今天在卡塔尔发生了这样的事情。
as world champion and today in Qatar it happened.
como campeón del mundo y hoy en Catar se dio.
以及发生的最后一场战斗。
and the last battle that takes place.
y la última batalla que da de lecho.
好吧，这是最后一次了。
And well, it was the last one.
Y bueno, fue la última.
最后的车站。
The last Stand.
La última batalla.
你说得很清楚了。
You had it very clear.
Lo tenías bien clarito.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
15 年。
15 years.
15 años.
10 个月后的选举，你的俱乐部。
and in 10 months the elections, your club.
y 10 meses las elecciones, tu club.
你能告诉我吗？
Can you tell?
¿Se puede decir?
是的，是的，事实是这样。
Yes, yes, the truth is.
Sí, sí, la verdad que sí.
事实是……
The truth is that...
La verdad que...
当你开始的时候，很难想象你可以在同一个地方度过这么多年。
When you start it is difficult to think that you can spend so many years in the same place.
Cuando uno empieza es difícil de llegar a pensar que puede pasar tantos años en un mismo lugar.
以及更多通过习惯你的国家的衬衫。
and more by getting used to your country's shirt.
y más habituando la camiseta de tu país.
我认为很难在那里继续下去。
I think it's difficult to be there, to continue.
Creo que es difícil de poder estar, de seguir.
我想你们是最常看到人们进入、离开、有人来、有人来的这些事情的人。
I think you are the ones who see the most all those things about people entering, leaving, some coming, others coming.
Creo que ustedes son los que más ven todas esas cosas de que entran, salen, vienen unos, vienen otros.
很难在我的整个职业生涯中一直保持这样的状态
and it is difficult to be able to maintain and have been throughout my career, to have been able
y es difícil de poder mantenerse y haber estado durante toda mi carrera, haber podido
入选国家队对我来说是一件难忘的事情。
Being in the National Team is something unforgettable for me.
Estar en la Selección es algo inolvidable para mí.
你喜欢吗？
Did you enjoy it?
¿Lo disfrutaste?
有时不，有时是。
At times no, at times yes.
Por momentos no, por momentos sí.
我想有一些时刻...
I think there were moments...
Creo que hubo momentos...
当世界杯在他20多岁的时候开始时，那真是太美好了，南美人，当他还是个孩子的时候，奥运会
It was beautiful when the World Cup began in his 20s, the South American, when he was a boy the Olympics that were
hermoso cuando empezó todo mundial su 20, el sudamericano, cuando era chico las olimpiadas que fueron
当局的。
of the authorities.
de las autoridades.
突然之间，我在决赛中进球了，因为我能够见到这么多球员。
out of nowhere and I ended up scoring a goal in a final, having been able to meet so many players.
de la nada y terminé haciendo gol de una final, haber podido conocer a tantos jugadores.
在经历了那些艰难的时期之后，
After the difficult times I went through,
Después de los momentos difíciles que pasé,
我认为有比我喜欢的更多的事情，但是，嘿，所有这些也让我坚强地停下来。
I think there were more than I enjoyed, but hey, all of that also made me strong to stop.
creo que fueron más de los que disfruté, pero bueno, todo eso también me hizo fuerte parar.
对于最终发生的事情，一切美好的事情都发生了，我能够享受。
for what came in the end, that everything nice came and I was able to enjoy.
para lo que vino al final, que vino todo lo lindo y pude disfrutar.
至少以一种好的方式结束了我在国家队的职业生涯。
at least the end of my career in the national team in a good way.
por lo menos el final de mi carrera en la selección de una buena manera.
在预览中你说我还没有准备好参加最后一场比赛。
In the preview you said I'm not ready for my last game.
En la previa decías no estoy preparado para mi último partido.
现在你已经是一名前国家队球员了。
and now that you are a former national team player.
y ahora que sos un ex jugador de la selección.
不，现在...现在就是这样，我想...
No, now... now that's it, I think...
No, ahora... ahora ya está, creo que...
有一天我意识到我是。
The other day I realized I was.
El otro día me di cuenta que estaba.
我意识到为什么不...
I realized why not...
Me di cuenta porque no...
我并不担心名单会出来，我知道它不会在那里，所以我......
I wasn't anxious that the list was going to come out, I knew it wasn't going to be there, so I was...
No estaba con esa ansiedad de que iba a salir la lista, sabía que no iba a estar, entonces estaba...
就像另一天，当我准备好的时候。
Like another day, when I was ready.
como un día más, cuando ya era lista.
我看到很多人开始进步，就在那时我意识到了这一点。
I saw that many were starting to get on and that's when I realized it.
Vi que muchos se empezaban a subir y ahí me di cuenta.
就好像我意识到是时候了，是正确的时间了，是我必须离开的时候了。
It was like I realized that it was time, it was the right time, it was the time I had to leave.
como que me di cuenta que era el momento, era el momento indicado, era el momento en el que tenía que dejar.
我非常享受过去的几年，我认为
I have enjoyed these last few years very much and I think that
disfruté estos últimos años muchísimo y creo que
我所享受的一切都超过了我所经历的所有糟糕时光，这对我来说是至关重要的。
that everything I enjoyed outweighed all the bad times I had and for me that is fundamental.
que todo eso que disfruté superó todos los malos momentos que pasé y para mí eso es fundamental.
以防万一，你查过清单了吗？
Just in case, did you check the list?
¿Por las dudas la revisaste la lista?
不不不，我的想法就是上面那个。
No, no, my idea is just like that above.
No, no, mi idea es así por arriba nomás.
看看那里的男孩们，那是因为现在好了
to see the boys who were there and that's because well now
para ver los chicos que estaban y eso porque bueno ahora
我也是国家队的球迷，我希望国家队表现出色......
I am another fan of the National Team and I want the National Team to do well...
Soy un hincha más de la Selección y quiero que la Selección le vaya...
到目前为止一切进展顺利。
It's going well as it has been up to now.
le vaya bien como hasta ahora.
我认为有一个非常好的一代......
I think there is a very nice generation of...
Creo que hay una generación muy linda de...
一批高素质的球员开始进入大俱乐部，这一点很重要。
of players with a lot of quality who are beginning to be in big clubs and that is important.
de jugadores con muchísima calidad que empiezan a estar en grandes clubes y eso es importante.
如果医生没有告诉你妈妈去打球，会发生什么？
If the doctor didn't tell your mom to go play ball, what would happen?
Si el médico no le decía a tu mamá que vayas a jugar a la pelota, ¿qué pasaba?
没什么，我想今天我会非常自豪地和我的老人在煤厂工作，我会继续......
And nothing, I think that today I would be working with great pride with my old man in the coal factory, I would have continued...
Y nada, creo que hoy estaría laburando con mucho orgullo con mi viejo en la carbonería, hubiese seguido...
平静地在那里，我什么都不相信
there calmly and I believe nothing
ahí tranquilamente y nada creo que
如果一件事或另一件事是同一个人，它也会以同样的方式继续下去。
If one thing or the other had been the same person, it would have continued in the same way.
que una cosa o la otra hubiese sido la misma persona, hubiese seguido de la misma manera.
上帝给了我机会和那位医生，让我成为了今天的我。
God gave me the possibility and that doctor to make me who I am today.
Dios me dio la posibilidad y ese doctor de que hoy sea quien soy.
没什么，为我一生中所建立的一切感到自豪。
And nothing, proud of what I built in my life.
Y nada, orgulloso de lo que construí en mi vida.
15年了，你几乎放弃了一切？
15 years and you almost left everything?
¿15 años y casi dejás todo?
这一切怎么样？
How was all that?
¿Cómo fue todo eso?
是的，是的，开始了……
Yes, yes, it started...
Sí, sí, arrancó...
当我第一次去中心买那个 25 号球时，我才七岁。
I was seven years old when I went to the center for the first time, to buy that 25 ball.
con siete años cuando fui al central por primera vez, por la compra de esa 25 pelota.
从那时起，一切都开始得很好，当我 15 岁左右时，我进入了我的第一个。
From there everything started very nicely and when I was 15 or so I was in my first one.
A partir de ahí arrancó todo muy lindo y cuando tenía 15 años más o menos estuve en mi primera.
我第一次撞到墙上，撞到一名技术人员......
My first crash against the wall, against a technician who...
Mi primer choque contra la pared, contra un técnico que...
他喜欢那些打人、打人、碰撞的人。
that he liked people who hit, who hit, who collided.
que le gustaba la gente que golpeaba, que pegaba, que chocaba.
他不喜欢那些玩游戏的人，他告诉我他是个狗屎，他不会跳到头上，他不会摔倒。
He didn't like those who played and he told me that he was a shit, that he didn't jump to head, that he didn't crash.
No le gustaban los que jugaban y me dijo que era un cagón, que no saltaba a cabecear, que no chocaba.
他不会踏上脚步，好吧，他告诉我的老太婆，她应该去别的地方。
that he wouldn't set foot and well, he told my old woman that she should go somewhere else.
que no ponía el pie y bueno le dijo a mi vieja como para que me vaya a otro lado
我的老太婆已经告诉我不，她要继续在那里，她要继续与他战斗
and my old woman already told me no, that she was going to continue there, that she was going to continue fighting him
y ya mi vieja me dijo que no, que iba a seguir ahí, que le iba a seguir peleando
好吧，那是第一次撞墙，从那里我继续与之斗争。
And well, that was the first crash against the wall and from there I continued fighting it.
Y bueno, ese fue el primer choque contra la pared y a partir de ahí seguí peleándola.
你还说我不玩了？
And there you said I don't play anymore?
¿Y ahí dijiste no juego más?
我在那里说我不再玩了，但是嘿，我身后总是有我的老太太......
There I said I don't play anymore, but hey, I always had my old lady behind who...
Ahí dije no juego más, pero bueno, tenía a mi vieja siempre atrás que...
谁热爱足球，谁就热爱足球。
who loves football, who loves what football is.
que le encanta el fútbol, que ama lo que es el fútbol.
她希望我继续玩，继续……
She wanted me to continue playing, to continue...
Ella quería que yo siga jugando, que siga...
梦想着有一天能够到达，这就是我在那里的原因。
Dreaming of the dream of being able to arrive one day and that's why I am there.
Soñando con el sueño de poder llegar algún día y por eso soy ahí.
你知道他们把你放在同样的高度或登上领奖台吗？
Are you aware that they put you at the same height or on the podium?
¿Sos consciente que te ponen a la misma altura o en el podio?
梅西，马拉多纳，迪玛利亚，迪玛利亚，梅西，马拉多纳。
Messi, Maradona, Di María, Di María, Messi, Maradona.
换句话说，他们是贯穿球队历史的三个名字。
In other words, they are the three names that appear throughout the history of the team.
O sea, son los tres nombres que a lo largo de la historia de la selección aparecen.
嗯，我想，就像我说的，这对其他所有人来说都是一个问题或问题。
Well, I guess, like I said, that's a question or something for everyone else.
Bueno, creo que, como ya dije, eso es una pregunta o es algo para los demás.
我很自豪能够在那里，即使我在那里，也好像我先在那里，因为迭戈和利奥......
I am proud to be able to be there, even if I am there it is as if I had first because Diego and Leo are...
a mí me enorgullece poder estar ahí igual si estoy ahí es como si tuviese primero porque Diego y Leo son...
他们来自另一个星球，所以假设我是第一个，如果是这样的话。
They are from another planet so let's say I'm first if that's the case.
son de otro planeta así que digamos que estoy primero si es así
但不，事实是，我感到自豪，经过这么多的牺牲，经过这么多的战斗，经过痛苦......
But no, the truth is that I am proud that after so much sacrifice, after fighting so much, after suffering...
Pero no, la verdad que me enorgullece que después de tanto sacrificio, después de pelearla tanto, de sufrir...
今天能够来到现场或者跻身前五名对我来说是一件非常好的事情。
Today being able to be there or be among the first five for me is something very nice.
hoy poder estar ahí o estar entre los cinco primero para mí es algo muy lindo.
在阿伦加，梅西在半决赛前说，让我们为他、为你而努力。
In the Arenga, Messi, before the semifinal, said, let's do it for him, for you.
En la Arenga, Messi, previo a la semifinal, dijo, hagámoslo por él, por vos.
在决赛的Renga中。
in the Renga of the final.
en la Renga de la final.
不，最后一轮是针对所有人的。
No, in the final round it was for everyone.
No, en la resa de la final ya era por todos.
那是因为它是...
It was because it was...
Era porque era...
我的最后一场是因为这是一场新的决赛，因为我们必须继续证明，因为……
My last one because it was a new final, because we had to continue proving, because...
El último mío porque era una nueva final, porque teníamos que seguir demostrando, porque...
关于哥伦比亚以及他们的比赛方式有很多讨论。
There was a lot of talk about Colombia, about how they were playing.
Se hablaba mucho de Colombia, de cómo estaban jugando.
对于我们来说，我们知道这是一个艰难的选择，但是......
And for us we knew it was a difficult selection, but...
Y para nosotros sabíamos que era una selección difícil, pero...
但通过像我们一直在做的那样玩我们的游戏和战斗，我们很有可能再次成为
but that by playing our game and fighting as we had been doing, it was very likely that we could be again
pero que nosotros haciendo nuestro juego y peleando como lo veníamos haciendo era muy probable que podamos volver a ser
冠军，当你在半决赛的擂台上听到这句话时，让我们为他做这件事
champions and when you heard it in the ring in the semifinal let's do it for him
campeones y cuando lo escuchaste en la ringa de la semifinal hagámoslo por él
你看了什么？
What did you look at?
que lo miraste?
不，这让我感到自豪，这让我非常高兴，我记得这个故事
No, it makes me proud, it makes me very happy, that I remember the story
No, me enorgullece, me hace muy feliz, que me acorde la historia
我在半决赛​​之前正在考虑一个问题，我认为...
that I'm thinking about one before a semi-final, I think it's...
que esté pensando en uno antes de una semifinal, creo que es...
这对我来说是一种荣幸，而且显然我对他怀有深厚的感情。
It is a privilege for me and it is obvious that I have enormous affection for him.
Es un privilegio para mí y es obvio que le tengo un cariño enorme a él.
不仅因为球场上的情况，还因为球场外的情况。
not only for what it is on the field but for what it is outside.
no solamente por lo que es dentro de la cancha sino por lo que es fuera.
总决赛对你的打击比伤病更严重，或者说伤病对你的打击比决赛更严重。
the finals hit you harder than the injuries or the injuries hit you harder than the finals.
las finales te golpearon más que las lesiones o las lesiones te golpearon más que las finales.
伤病对我的打击比决赛更严重，因为……
The injuries hit me much harder than the finals because...
Las lesiones me golpearon mucho más que las finales porque...
因为每次受伤都让我无法进入决赛。
because each injury prevented me from reaching those finals.
porque cada lesión me impidió poder llegar a esas finales.
这让我在决赛中无法百分百发挥。
It prevented me from being 100% in those finals.
me impidió haber podido estar al 100% en esas finales.
我认为所有的伤害都导致...
I think all the injuries led to...
Creo que todas las lesiones llevaron a...
无法参加决赛，最后一切都是狗屎，可以这么说。
to not being able to play in the finals, and in the end it's all shit, so to speak.
a no poder jugar a finales, y al final es toda una mierda, por así decirlo.
每场比赛我都会给自己施加压力。
I put pressure on myself in every game.
Me hacía la presión yo mismo en cada partido.
他是你最大的敌人。
He was your worst enemy.
Era tu peor enemigo.
他是我的第一个敌人。
He was my first enemy.
Era mi primer enemigo.
我听了很多外人的意见，也给自己施加了压力。
I listened a lot to outsiders and I put pressure on myself.
Escuchaba mucho a la fuera y yo mismo me ponía la presión.
在通行证中，在定义中，在一切事物中，我认为
in the passes, in the definitions, in everything and I think that
en los pases, en las definiciones, en todo y creo que
我只是对自己做了坏事和好事，直到我最终意识到这一点，我释放了自己。
That I was only doing myself bad and good until I ended up realizing it, I discharged myself.
que eso yo solo me estaba haciendo mal y bueno hasta que me terminé dando cuenta me di el alta
从那时起，一切开始变得更好。
And from there everything started to get better.
Y a partir de ahí todo empezó a estar mejor.
对我来说，你们是阿根廷足球最优秀一代的一部分。
For me you are part, generationally, of the best generation that Argentine football produced.
Para mí sos parte, generacionalmente, de la mejor generación que dio el fútbol argentino.
但这些头衔是由年轻人和那一代的一些代表人物组成的。
but the titles came with this mix of youth and some exponents of that generation.
pero los títulos llegaron con esta mezcla de juventud y algunos exponentes de esa generación.
那一代人为什么不奉献呢？
Why didn't that generation consecrate?
¿Por qué esa generación no consagró?
如果现在你回过头来说，缺少了什么？
If now you look back and say, what was missing?
Si ahora mirás para atrás y decís, ¿qué faltó?
我一直非常依赖足球，这也需要一点运气。
I always rely a lot on football, which also needs that touch of luck.
Yo siempre me baso mucho en el fútbol que también necesita ese toque de suerte.
在我的职业生涯中多次
and in my career many times
y en mi carrera muchas veces
或者绝大多数时候，这一切最终发生在我身上都是因为运气，而不是其他什么。
or the vast majority of the time it ended up happening to me by luck more than anything else.
o la gran mayoría de las veces me terminó pasando por suerte más que por otra cosa.
我认为那一代人缺乏运气。
And I think that generation lacked luck.
Y yo creo que a esa generación les faltó suerte.
我们做了...
We did...
Hicimos...
2014 年是一届伟大的世界杯，两届美洲杯都非常精彩。
A great World Cup in 2014, two very good America's Cups.
Un gran mundial en el 2014, dos muy buenas Copas de América.
如果我们进入了决赛，但没有实现，我们总是碰壁，不能崩溃。
And if we reached the finals and it was not achieved and we always hit the wall and could not collapse.
Y si llegamos a finales y no se logró y se chocó siempre contra la pared y no se podía derrumbar.
它最终杀死了我们。
and it ended up killing us.
y a nosotros nos terminó matando.
有很多玩家彻底消失了。
There are many players who completely disappeared.
Hay muchos jugadores que desaparecieron completamente.
许多男孩的地图几乎不再被谈论。
of the map of many boys that is hardly even talked about anymore.
del mapa de muchos chicos que casi ni se habla ya.
我认为这对我来说是非常痛苦的。
And I think that for me is very painful.
Y creo que eso para mí es muy doloroso.
我和他们一起生活了很多年，今天我能够站在另一边了。
I lived a lot with them and today I was able to be on the other side.
Conviví muchísimo con ellos y el hoy haber podido estar del otro lado.
我里面还留着那个。
I still have that inside.
sigo teniendo eso dentro.
每当我最终随国家队获胜时，我总是命名他，因为
Whenever I ended up winning now with the national team, I always named him because
Siempre que terminé ganando ahora con la selección, siempre lo nombré porque
对我来说，他们教会了我很多东西，他们教会了我为了继续追上她而做出的牺牲。
For me, they taught me a lot and they taught me what the sacrifice is to keep catching her.
Para mí me enseñaron muchísimo y me enseñaron lo que es el sacrificio de seguir pillándola.
最糟糕的...
Worst...
Lo peor...
所有后续行动。
of all that follow-up.
de toda esa seguidicia.
最糟糕的是第二次输掉美洲杯。
The worst was the second lost Copa América.
Lo peor fue la segunda Copa América perdida.
那时一切都崩溃了。
That's when everything ended up collapsing.
Ahí fue cuando se terminó de derrumbar todo.
我想我当时...
I think I was...
Creo que estaba...
直到第一届美洲杯失利之前，我们一直抱有这样的幻想
Until the first lost Copa América we continued with the illusion of that
hasta la primera Copa América perdida seguíamos con la ilusión con eso de
我们可以实现这一目标，我们已经很接近了，但是，在第二个之后，它是......
that we could achieve it, that we were close, but well, after the second one it was...
de poder lograrlo, de que estábamos cerca, pero bueno, después de la segunda fue...
最沉重的打击是当许多人开始离开国家队时。
The hardest blow there was when many began to leave the national team.
El golpe más duro que ahí fue cuando empezaron muchos a dejar la selección.
曾经？
Ever?
¿Alguna vez?
你是否曾犹豫过，或者你是否即将像里奥那样对国家队说“不”？
Did you hesitate or were you close to doing what Leo did and saying no to the national team?
¿Dudaste o estuviste cerca de hacer lo que hizo Leo de decirle que no a la selección?
是的，我确实有好几次他想离开。
Yes, I did have several times where he wanted to leave.
Sí, sí tuve varias veces en la que él quiso dejar.
那是在第二届美洲杯之后。
which was after the second Copa América.
que fue después de la segunda Copa América.
我也曾一度想放弃，但是……
There was a bit where I wanted to quit too, but well...
Ahí estuvo un poco en que quería dejar también, pero bueno...
我的妻子总是在那里坚持要我继续，在某些时候我会放弃。
My wife was always back there, insisting that I continue, that at some point I was going to give up.
Mi mujer siempre estuvo ahí atrás, insistiéndome con que siga, que en algún momento se me iba a dar.
我妈妈也是，然后2019年我们也输了。
My mom too, then 2019 happened that we lost too.
Mi mamá también, después pasó la del 2019 que perdemos también.
在那里我也再次产生了疑问。
There I was also in doubt again.
Ahí también estuve en duda otra vez.
我的母亲也在场，告诉我停止，停止痛苦，停止度过糟糕的时光，什么都不要，你看。
My mother was also there and told me to stop, to stop suffering, to stop having a bad time and nothing, you see.
Mi mamá también ahí ya me decía que deje, que deje de sufrir, que deje de pasarla mal y nada, viste.
在阿根廷，如果你没赢，那你就是失败者。
In Argentina if you don't win, you are a failure.
en Argentina si no ganas, sos un fracasado.
而这一切都已经达到了我的极限。
and all that had already reached my limit.
y todo eso ya me había llegado como a un límite.
我的妻子再次对我说不，我一直、一直、一直跟她争吵。
Once again I had my wife back there saying no, I kept, kept, kept fighting her.
Otra vez tuve a mi mujer ahí atrás diciendo no, seguí, seguí, seguí peleándola.
直到他们不再召唤你的那一天。
until the day they no longer summon you.
hasta el día que no te citen más.
嗯，最后我没注意，因为我现在就走了。
Well, in the end I didn't pay attention because I ended up leaving now.
Bueno, al final no hice caso porque terminé dejando yo ahora.
但我继续坚持下去，我继续战斗。
but I continued a little more, I kept fighting.
pero seguí un poco más, seguí peleando.
是她向我坚持说...
It was she who insisted to me that...
Fue ella que me insistió en que...
出来说话，表明她想去那里，因为……因为好吧，她……
to come out and talk, to show that she wanted to be there because... because well, she...
en que salga a hablar, en que demuestre que quería estar porque... porque bueno, ella...
他告诉我，如果你不知道如何说话，如果你不表现出你想在那里，你就不会在那里，而不是因为你在那里。
He told me, if you don't know how to speak, if you don't show that you want to be there, you won't be there, not because you are there.
Me decía, si no sabés hablar, si no demostrás que querés estar, no vas a estar, no porque estés.
他们会在每场比赛中进球并助攻，新一代即将到来，即使还没有被证明是优秀的。
scoring goals and assists every game they will call you, a new generation is coming, if not proven and good.
haciendo goles y asistencia cada partido te van a llamar, viene una nueva generación, si no demostradas y bueno.
这就是为什么我也决定出去演讲，以表明我想继续留在那里。
That's why I also made that decision to go out and speak, to show that I wanted to continue being there.
Por eso también tomé esa decisión de salir a hablar, de demostrar que quería seguir estando.
我再次与埃斯卡隆交谈，在那之后我给出了，嗯，从那里......
I spoke to Escalón again and after that note I gave, well, from there...
Volví a hablar con Escalón y después de esa nota que di, bueno, a partir de ahí...
你以为你不说一步就不会改变吗？
Do you think that if you didn't speak a step and it didn't change?
¿Crees que si no hablabas escalón y no cambiaba?
他告诉我不，但我相信，正如我妻子所相信的那样，我也相信这一点。
He tells me no, but I believe that, as my wife believed, I believe so.
Él me dice que no, pero yo creo que, como creía mi mujer, creo que sí.
如果我不出来说话，我想我可能就回不来了。
If I didn't come out to talk, I think I might not be back.
Si no salía a hablar, yo creo que podía no volver a estar.
近年来我所受到的热烈欢迎对我和我的家人来说是难忘的……
The ovations I received in recent years were unforgettable for me and my family who...
las ovaciones que recibí los últimos años fue inolvidable para mí y para mi familia que...
我不需要它，但我的家人更需要它，他...
that I didn't need it, but my family needed it more, he...
que no la necesitaba yo, sino la necesitaba más mi familia, el...
我老婆说过很多次了，对吧？
My wife said it many times, right?
Lo dijo muchas veces mi mujer, ¿no?
那个已经在球场上的人......
The one who was already on the court and...
El que ya estaba en la cancha y...
听说他们在对我发牢骚，然后……
And hearing that they were bitching at me and that and...
Y escuchar que me puteaban y eso y...
我的父亲和母亲在那里聆听并承受着痛苦。
and my father and my mother were there listening and suffering.
y que estaba mi viejo y mi mamá ahí escuchando y sufriendo.
这是最让你感动的，对吧？
It's what makes you the most, right?
Es lo que a uno le hace más, ¿no?
那个伤害一个人的人。
The one who hurts one.
Al que a uno le lastima.
但现在能够听到欢呼声了。
But now to be able to hear the cheers.
Pero ahora el poder escuchar las ovaciones.
说到底，最让我高兴的是，我的老头子和我的老头子现在都听话了。
In the end it is what makes me the most happy, that my old man and my old man listen now.
Al final es lo que más me hace feliz, el que mi viejo y mi viejo escuchen ahora.
divarillo、fideo、fideo 是最重要的东西。
The divarillo, the fideo, the fideo is the biggest thing there is.
El divarillo, el fideo, el fideo es lo más grande que hay.
无聊，不。
Boring, no.
Chata, no.
我不再想要任何东西，我没有要求任何更多的东西，最后我得到了，什么也没有，对我来说这是最多的。
I didn't want anything more, I didn't ask for anything more than that and I had it in the end and nothing, for me it is the most.
No quería más nada, no pedía más nada que eso y lo tuve al final y nada, para mí es lo más.
最可爱的事情。
The cutest thing.
Lo más lindo.
最好的搭配...
The best match...
El mejor partido...
对阵法国的决赛，对阵法国的决赛我认为是……
The final against France, the final against France I think it was...
La final contra Francia, la final contra Francia creo que fue...
我在国家队踢得最好的一场比赛。
One of my best games in the National Team.
Uno de mis mejores partidos en la Selección.
我认为这是 70、75 分钟...
I think it was 70, 75 minutes in which...
Creo que fueron 70, 75 minutos en lo que...
我什至不相信我所做的事，因为好吧......
I don't even believe what I did, because well...
en lo que ni yo creo lo que hice, porque bueno...
之后我看了比赛，决赛时我又看了两三遍。
I watched the games afterwards, I watched them again like two or three times in the final.
Miré los partidos después, los volví a ver como dos o tres veces a la final.
我所做的事情，我如何移动，我如何做事，我想......
and the things that I did, how I moved, how I did things, I think...
y las cosas que hice, cómo me moví, cómo hice las cosas, creo que...
毫无疑问，这是我在国家队打过的最好的比赛之一。
It was one of the best games I played in the National Team, without a doubt.
Que fue uno de los mejores partidos que hice en la Selección, sin duda.
你哭得最多的时候是？
The time you cried the most?
¿La vez que más lloraste?
也许不是因为喜悦或悲伤，但你说什么，他就不会停止哭泣。
Maybe not from joy or sadness, but what do you say, he doesn't stop crying.
Quizás no de alegría o de tristeza, pero que decís, no para de llorar.
就在那时我们赢得了美洲杯。
And that's when we won the Copa América.
Y es cuando ganamos la Copa América.
就在那时，那堵墙彻底破裂，拱门打开了。
That was when that wall finished breaking, when the arch opened.
que fue ahí cuando se termina de romper esa pared, cuando se abre el arco.
对阵巴西队是我最沮丧的时候。
Against Brazil was when I was most upset.
contra Brasil fue cuando más me sobé.
然后，最后却是……
Then, in the end it was...
Después, al final fue el...
我想我们后来又赢得了一切，但是......
I think we won everything again later, but...
Creo que después volvimos a ganar todo, pero...
我最享受的一天是因为那是我们终于能够打破那堵墙的时候。
The day I enjoyed the most was that because it was when we were finally able to break that wall.
El día que más disfruté fue ese porque fue cuando por fin pudimos romper esa pared.
我的……根据定义或……你那里有什么。
my... by definition or by... What you have there.
mi... por definición o por... Lo que vos lo tenes ahí.
决赛对阵法国，顾名思义，就是对阵意大利。
by play to the final against France, by definition against Italy.
por jugada a la final contra Francia, por definición contra Italia.
我认为我对阵多纳卢马的进球是因为速度和我的定义
I think the goal I scored against Donaluma was because of the speed and how I define
Creo que el gol que le hago a Donaluma por la velocidad y por cómo defino
在这么小的空间，这么大的多纳鲁马，定义是……
In so little space, so big Donnarumma, the definition was...
En tan poquito espacio, tan grandote Donnarumma, la definición fue...
这真是太壮观了，然后进球......
It was spectacular and then the goal against...
fue espectacular y después el gol contra...
我认为对阵法国队的比赛是阿根廷队中最好的一场，也是你喊得最多的一场
against France in play was I think one of the best of the Argentine team and the one you shouted the most
contra francia en jugada fue creo que una de las mejores de la selección argentina y el que más gritaste
这就是我吐露的心声。
That's what I've gotten off my chest.
Es lo que me he desahogado.
我认为对阵法国队的比赛是我尖叫得最多的一场。
I think against France it was the one I screamed the most.
Creo que contra Francia fue el que más grité.
对阵巴西时我喊出了这句话，但我怀疑这是否是乌尔萨，如果不是……
Against Brazil I shouted it, but I was in doubt if it was Ursa and if not...
Contra Brasil lo grité, pero estaba en duda si era Ursa y si no...
谁看了一切，不，不，但是在法国，在法国，这完全是一种消耗。
who looked at everything, no, no, but the one in France, the one in France was, it was a complete drain.
que miraba todo, no, no, pero el de Francia, el de Francia fue, fue un desagüo completo.
心脏是在葡萄牙出生的吗？
Was the heart born here in Portugal?
¿Acá nació en Portugal el corazón?
他出生在这里，他出生在这里……
He was born here, he was born here in...
Acá nació, acá nació en...
心与善走遍了许多国家、许多城市。
The heart and goodness traveled through many countries, many cities.
el corazón y bueno recorrió muchísimos países, muchísimas ciudades.
好吧，今天我们再次来到这里并努力继续这样做。
And well, today we are here again and trying to continue doing it.
Y bueno, hoy por hoy estamos otra vez acá e intentando seguir haciéndolo.
你今天用那个表情符号吗？
Do you use that emoji today?
¿Hoy ese emoji lo usas?
我用它，是的，我经常使用它。
I use it yes, I use it a lot.
Lo uso sí, lo uso bastante.
和家人还是和大家一起？
With the family or with everyone?
¿Con la familia o con todos?
与大家，与大家。
With everyone, with everyone.
Con todos, con todos.
是你的印章吗？
Is it your seal?
¿Es tu sello?
是的，是的，是的。
Yes, yes, yes.
Sí, sí, sí.
是的，因为正如你所说，已经……
Yes, because it has already been, as you said, already...
Sí, porque ya lleva, como dijiste, ya...
我已经这样做了 14 或 15 年，直到我挂靴的那一天，它都会继续存在。
14 or 15 years doing it and until the day I hang up my boots it will continue to be there.
14 o 15 años haciéndolo y hasta el día que cuelgue los botines va a seguir estando.
前三名教练很难吧？
Top 3 coaches Difficult, huh?
Top 3 de entrenadores Difícil, ¿eh?
呃……
Ehhh...
毫无疑问，它升级到了我身上。
It escalated to me without a doubt.
Me escaló ni sin duda.
他在各方面都是一位出色的教练。
He is a great coach in every way.
Es un gran entrenador en todo sentido.
对于他拥有的教练组，对于如何......
for the coaching staff he has, for how...
por el cuerpo técnico que tiene, por cómo...
他与球员有这种联系，他处理比赛的方式是......
He has that connection with the player and the way he approaches the games is...
tiene esa conexión con el jugador y por cómo plantea los partidos es...
太完美了。
It's perfect.
Es perfecto.
我认为他是最好的之一。
I think he is one of the best.
Creo que es uno de los mejores.
后来亚历杭德罗也是一位对我影响巨大的教练。
Later, Alejandro was also a coach who had a huge impact on me.
Después, Alejandro también fue un entrenador que me marcó muchísimo.
我和他一起学到了很多东西。
I learned a lot with him.
Aprendí muchísimo con él.
然后就很难了。
and then it was difficult.
y después fue difícil.
我有很多教练，穆里尼奥、安杰洛蒂、
I had many coaches, Mourinho, Angelotti,
Tuve muchos entrenadores, Mourinho, Angelotti,
我想我经历过很多优秀的教练，所以很难
I think I've been through so many good coaches that it's hard to
Creo que pasé por tantos entrenadores tan buenos que es difícil de poder
最糟糕的是范加尔，我向你保证，我毫不怀疑，我之前已经告诉过你了。
The worst is Van Gaal, I assure you that, I have no doubt, I have already told you before.
El peor es Van Gaal, eso te lo aseguro, no tengo ninguna duda, ya te lo he dicho antes.
但对于最好的，很难告诉你三个。
but of the best it is difficult to be able to tell you three.
pero de los mejores es difícil de poder decirte tres.
我想我曾经...
I think I had...
Creo que tuve...
他有伟大的球员，伟大的教练，他们都加入了，他们都教我。
He had great players, great coaches, who all joined in, they all taught me.
Tuvo grandísimos jugadores, grandísimos entrenadores, que todos embarcaron, todos me enseñaron.
但是，嘿，他们就在那里。
But hey, they are among those there.
Pero bueno, están entre esos ahí.
如果我必须告诉你，那就很难了。
If I have to tell you, it's difficult.
Si te tengo que decir, es difícil.
但是，嘿，无论他是否有过教练生涯，这些都是最好的。
But hey, those are some of the best. Regardless of whether he had a career as a coach or not.
Pero bueno, esos son de los mejores Más allá de si hizo carrera como entrenador o no
迭戈指导你了吗？
Did Diego direct you?
¿Te dirigió el Diego?
是的，我不会让迭戈担任你的教练，因为......
Yes, I don't put Diego as your coach because...
Sí, al Diego no te lo pongo como entrenador porque...
因为对我来说他更多的是一个朋友，他更多的是...
Because for me he was more of a friend, he was more of a...
Porque para mí era más un amigo, era más una...
一个同伴，一个整夜过来聊天的人。
a companion, a person who came up all night to chat.
un compañero, una persona que se acercaba toda la noche a charlar.
他看起来不像是一个教练，他更像是一个朋友、一个兄弟、一个父亲。
He didn't seem like a coach, he seemed more like a friend, a brother, a dad.
No parecía un entrenador, parecía más un amigo, un hermano, un papá.
这句话我说过很多次了，我把它当成国家队的木瓜比什么都重要。
I said it many times and I took it more as a papaya in the national team than anything else.
Lo dije muchas veces y lo tomé más como un papaya dentro en la selección que otra cosa.
当没有人支持我的时候，他支持我。
He supported me when no one supported me.
Me bancó cuando nadie me bancaba.
他让我向前迈出了一步。
He gave me a step forward.
me dio para adelante.
每次他批评我，最让我失望的一次。
Every time he criticized me, the most he put me down.
en todo momento que me criticaba, el más me ponía.
他越骂我，就越让我难堪。
The more he bitched at me, the more he put me on.
más me puteaba, más me ponía.
没什么，老实说，我认为迭戈对我来说就是一切。
Nothing, I think Diego was everything for me, honestly.
Nada, creo que fue todo para mí el Diego, sinceramente.
能够与里奥一起踢球并让迭戈担任教练。
having been able to play with Leo and having Diego as a coach.
el haber podido jugar con Leo y el tenerlo a Diego de entrenador.
在赢得一切之后，我想就这样了。
and after having won everything, I think that's it.
y después haber ganado todo, creo que ya está.
这是离开一切的好时机。
This was the right time to leave everything.
Este era el momento indicado para dejar todo.
他们不想要迪玛利亚，正是迪玛利亚使他永垂不朽。
And they didn't want Di María, who immortalized him.
Y a Di María no lo querían, que lo inmortalizó.
查塔，他们捐赠给迭戈的东西是世界上最伟大的东西。
Chata, what they donate to Diego is the greatest thing there is.
Chata, eso que donan a Diego es lo más grande que hay.
我总是说，对我来说，利奥是历史上最好的。
I always say, for me Leo is the best in history.
Siempre digo, para mí Leo es el mejor de la historia.
毫无疑问，他八次获得金球奖，进球数，助攻数，他所做的一切。
Without a doubt for the eight Ballon d'Ors, for the number of goals, for the number of assists, for everything he did.
Sin duda por los ocho balones de oro, por la cantidad de goles, por la cantidad de asistencia, por todo lo que hizo.
在他的整个职业生涯中，并将继续以他的方式行事。
throughout his career and continues to do it the way he is.
durante toda su carrera y sigue haciendo por como es.
但迭戈就是迭戈，他就是现实。
But Diego is Diego, he is reality.
Pero el Diego es el Diego, es la realidad.
你可以...
You can...
Vos podés...
不管怎么说，迭戈就是迭戈，对我来说，对阿根廷人来说，对世界来说，他就是迭戈。
say one thing or another but Diego is Diego, for me, for the Argentinian and for the world he is Diego.
decir una cosa u otra pero el Diego es el Diego, para mí, para el argentino y para el mundo es el Diego.
你有一个偶像吗？
An idol you had?
¿Un ídolo que tenías?
艾尔杀戮。
El Killing.
杀戮总是...
Killing was always...
El Killing siempre fue...
我的参考对象是那个总是在那里的人，因为他从中心出来，因为他踢球
My reference is the person who is always there because well he came out of center because he played
Mi referente la persona que siempre ahí porque bueno salió de central porque jugó
他在国家队踢球是因为那是我的位置，尽管……
He played in the national team because it was my position, although...
jugó en la selección porque era mi posición, aunque...
然后这些年来我的立场发生了变化。
Then my position changed over the years.
Después mi posición fue cambiando durante los años.
当我还是个孩子的时候，甚至当我出道的时候，我总是为
When I was a kid and even when I debuted I always played for
cuando era chico y hasta cuando debuté siempre jugué por
在左边，他是一名左中场，这和我和他的位置是一样的
on the left he was a left midfielder and well it was the same position as him and I always
por izquierda era un volante por izquierda y bueno era la misma posición que él y siempre me
反思一下。
reflect on it.
refleje en él.
你告诉他了吗？
Did you tell him?
¿Se lo dijiste?
是的，是的，直到今天我仍然多次说话。
Yes, yes, many times to this day I still talk.
Sí, sí, muchas veces hasta el día de hoy sigo hablando.
我为他观看联盟比赛...
I watch the union matches for him to...
miro los partidos de unión por él para...
试图给他力量，什么也没有，我认为他是一个优秀的人，对我来说他是......
to try to give him strength too and nothing, I think he is an excellent person, for me he is...
para intentar darle fuerzas también y nada, creo que es una excelente persona, para mi es...
更重要的是我的偶像总是教我，我有机会和他一起踢中卫，这对我来说就是一切。
It's more that my idol always taught me, I had the chance to play with him at center back and that was everything for me.
Es más que mi ídolo siempre me enseñó, tuve la posibilidad de jugar con él en central y ahí para mí fue todo.
他有没有对你说过一些让你终生难忘的话？
Did he say something to you that stayed with you forever?
¿Te dijo algo que te quedó para siempre?
是的，让他跑。
Yes, let him run.
Sí, que corra.
他总是告诉我，跑吧，狗娘养的，我必须跑，因为今天我 36 岁了。
He always told me, run, son of a bitch, I have to run because today I'm 36.
Siempre me decía, corre, hijo de puta, que tengo que correr porque hoy ya tengo 36.
嗯，我现在36岁了。
Well, I'm 36 now.
Bueno, ya ahora tengo 36.
所以不，他...你对他说什么？
So no, he... What do you say to him?
Así que no, él... ¿Qué le decís vos?
不，我什么也没对他说，我试图逃跑，但是哦，好吧。
No, I didn't say anything to him, I tried to run, but oh well.
No, no le decía nada, intentaba correr, pero bueno.
他为我做出了牺牲，他为我所做的一切是为了让我能够尝试做出改变，但什么也没有，总是……
He made the sacrifice for me and he did it for me so that I could try to make a difference, but nothing, always...
Él hacía el sacrificio por mí y me lo hacía adelante para que yo intentara hacer la diferencia, pero nada, siempre...
他总是对我很好，他总是在我身后，他总是试图......
He always gave me the good graces, he was always behind me, he always tried to...
Siempre me tiró la buena, siempre estuvo atrás mío, siempre me intentó...
教导我与他共度的短暂时光以及我离开后的每时每刻
teach in every moment the little time I had with him and after I left
enseñar en cada momento el poco tiempo que tuve con él y después de que me fui
很少，我和他没什么关系，然后我又和他有了关系……
very little, I had little relationship with him and then I had one again...
muy poco, tuve poca relación con él y después volví a tener una...
关系恢复并开始交谈很多，直到今天我的关系都很好。
a relationship back and start talking a lot and to this day I have a good relationship.
una relación de vuelta y empezar a hablar mucho y hasta el día de hoy tengo una buena relación.
我可以把玛丽亚的水平比梅西和马拉多纳低。
I can put María's at a lower level than Messi and Maradona.
La de María lo puedo poner a un nivel bajito de Messi y de Maradona.
你可以说马拉多纳和梅西是10岁，他是9岁。
You can say that Maradona and Messi are 10, he is 9.
Puede decir que Maradona y Messi son el 10, él es el 9.
你好迪玛丽亚，我非常爱你。
Hello Di María, I love you very much.
Hola Di María, te amo mucho.
你好迪玛丽亚，我爱你！
Hello Di María, I love you!
¡Hola Di María, te amo!
你好迪玛丽亚，你是我的最爱！
Hello Di María, you are my favorite!
¡Hola Di María, eres mi favorito!
科尔多瓦的亲爱的视频，我们铭记于心
Dear video of Córdoba that we carry inside our hearts
video querido de Córdoba que llevamos adentro del corazón
您无需执行任何其他操作。
You don't have to do anything else.
No tenés que hacer más nada.
你从来没有真正需要做任何事情。
You never really had to do anything.
En realidad nunca tuviste que hacer nada.
从一无所有中拯救自己，但你仍然坚持一切你力所能及的事情......
to redeem yourself from nothing, but still you insist on everything that was always within your reach and...
para redimirte de nada, pero aún así insistes en todo lo que siempre tuvo tu alcance y...
你把我们放在了顶端。
You put us at the top.
Nos pusiste en lo más alto.
谢谢。
Gracias.
你不需要做任何事。
You don't have to do anything.
No tenés que hacer nada.
好吧，最后...
Well, in the end...
Bueno, al final...
我想我会坚持这个，对吗？
I think I'll stick with this one, right?
Creo que me quedo con esta, ¿no?
他们在其中说谢谢，就是这样，我想......
in which they say thank you, that's it, I think...
en el que te digan gracias, ya está, creo que...
能够实现我所取得的一切，能够给予它......
having been able to achieve everything I achieved, having been able to give it the...
el haber podido lograr todo lo que logré, haber podido darle la...
祝所有阿根廷人，尤其是我的家人感到高兴。
Joy to all Argentines, to my family more than anything.
La alegría a todos los argentinos, a mi familia más que nada.
就这样。
That's all.
Es todo.
我认为，正如你所说，能够到达那里，
I think that, as you said, being able to be up there,
Creo que, como dijiste vos, el poder estar ahí arriba,
今天每个人都对你说谢谢，就是这样，它充满了我的心。
in which today everyone tells you thank you, that's it, it fills my heart.
en el que hoy todo el mundo te diga gracias, con eso ya está, me llena el corazón.
他不去管它，这就是为什么我说美洲杯是最后一件事，因为无论决赛中发生什么......
and he leaves it alone, that's why I said the Copa América was the last thing, because whatever happens in the final...
y se deja tranquilo, por eso la Copa América dije que era lo último, porque pase lo que pase en la final...
我知道我要穿过那扇大门，但什么也没有。
I knew I was going to go through the big door and nothing.
Sabía que me iba a ir por la puerta grande y nada.
让我们看看，我赢了，就这样。
Let's see, I've won it, that's it.
A ver, la he ganado, ya está.
我是从大门离开的，更多的是，所以我感谢所有的阿根廷人。
I left through the gate, much more, so I am grateful to all the Argentines.
Me fui por el portón, mucho más, así que agradecido a todos los argentinos.
我知道很多人批评我的伤病，批评我没有赢得比赛，但是……
I know that many people criticized me for my injuries, for not having won things, but...
Sé que muchos me putearon por mis lesiones, por no haber ganado cosas, pero...
但这也给了我继续下去的力量，但我知道很多人
but that gave me strength to continue also but I know that many
pero eso me dio fuerza para seguir también pero sé que muchos
或者至少绝大多数人都非常支持我，这也让我想继续下去。
or at least the vast majority supported me a lot and that also made me want to continue.
o por lo menos la gran mayoría me bancó muchísimo y eso me hizo también el querer seguir.
挣扎。
struggling.
luchando.
然后是技术总监、领导或其他什么人。
Then comes the technical director, the leader or whatever comes.
Después viene el director técnico, el dirigente o qué viene.
我正在参加教练课程，以防万一它适合我，你永远不知道。
I'm doing the coaching course in case it suits me, you never know.
Estoy haciendo el curso de entrenador por si me pinta, nunca se sabe.
我已经有一名助理了，因为 Lea 最近在其中一项工作中向我施加了压力……
I already have an assistant because Lea recently put pressure on me in one of...
Ayudante ya tengo porque me metió presión Lea hace poco en una entre...
他在一张便条中说，如果他参与其中，那也是我作为助理，所以……
in a note he gave that said that if he got involved it was with me as an assistant, so...
en una nota que dio que dijo que si se metía era conmigo de ayudante, entonces...
如果他出现的话我就会有一个助手，好吧，当我们在...
If he appears then I have an assistant, well, when we were in...
si le aparece entonces ya ayudante tengo, bueno ya cuando estábamos en...
我认为这一切都是从巴黎开始的。
I think all this started in Paris.
En Paris creo que arrancó todo esto.
他是一名教练，他是我的助理，我做好了准备，但我不知道会发生什么。
that he was a coach, he was my assistant and I prepared and I don't know what.
de que sí era un entrenador, era mi ayudante y preparar y no sé qué.
没什么，事实是，最重要的是，所有这些都出来了，因为，好吧，我们有一个
and nothing, the truth is that more than anything all of that came out because, well, we have a
y nada la verdad que más que nada todo eso salió porque bueno tenemos una
家庭之间的友谊非常好。
Very nice friendship between families.
Muy linda amistad entre familias.
这就是为什么这一切都会出现，但我这样做不仅仅是为了以防万一。
And that's why all this came out, but I'm doing it more than anything just in case.
Y por eso salió todo esto, pero lo estoy haciendo más que nada por las dudas.
我不知道，老实说，我总是说同样的话，如果你稍后再想的话，那是因为今天就要结束了……
And I don't know, honestly I always said the same thing, that if you think about later it's because today is ending and...
Y no sé, sinceramente siempre dije lo mismo, que si uno piensa en el después es porque el hoy se está terminando y...
事实上，我今天在今天，我没有考虑以后的事情，因为我仍然觉得我可以继续付出
and the truth is that today I am in today, I am not thinking about the later and it is because I still feel that I can continue giving
y la verdad que hoy estoy en el hoy no estoy pensando en el después y es porque todavía me siento que puedo seguir dando
他邀请你加入教练组并告诉你是否愿意来
much more step and he invited you to the coaching staff and told you if you want to come
mucho más escalón y te invitó al cuerpo técnico te dijo si quiere venir
他个人没有对我说什么，他一定是把它扔在那里了，他什么也没对我说，但是……
He didn't say anything to me personally, he must have thrown it there, he didn't say anything to me, but...
A mí no me dijo nada personalmente, la habrá tirado ahí, a mí no me dijo nada, pero...
但我认为他的教练组非常完美。
But I think the coaching staff he has is perfect.
Pero creo que el cuerpo técnico que tiene es perfecto.
一个人做一切事情，现在老实说......
a person for everything and honestly now...
una persona para cada cosa y sinceramente ya...
我已经很感激他了。
I'm already grateful to him.
Ya estoy agradecido a él.
你会改变什么吗？
Would you change anything?
¿Cambiarías algo?
不，不是真的。
No, not really.
No, la verdad que no.
事实是它不会改变任何事情。
The truth is that it wouldn't change anything.
La verdad que no cambiaría nada.
我想是的。
I think so.
Creo que sí.
如果我在国家队经历了所有的磨难才能够以这样的方式完成比赛，我会再做一次。
that if I suffered everything I suffered in the national team to be able to finish this way, I would do it again.
que si sufrí todo lo que sufrí en la selección para poder terminar de esta manera, lo volvería a hacer.
然后就我个人而言，我的生活和我的家庭是什么。
and then personally, in what my life is and what my family is.
y después en lo personal, en lo que es mi vida y en lo que es mi familia.
老实说，我拥有任何人想要的一切，我非常高兴。
I honestly have everything anyone could want and I am more than happy.
Sinceramente tengo todo lo que alguien puede desear y estoy más que feliz.